Guide to the Dean's Fellowship in History of Home Economics and Human Nutrition records,1991-2016.
Dean's Fellowship in History of Home Economics and Human Nutrition records,1991-2015.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dean's Fellowship in History of Home Economics and Human Nutrition records, 1991-2016.
23-2-3127
New York State College of Human Ecology.
1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, bulletins.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, recipient information, reports and publicity pertaining to the Dean's Fellowship, which was established in 1992 by Francille Firbaugh, following the 1991 New York State College of Human Ecology Conference "Rethinking Women and Home Economics in the 20th Century."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, recipient information, reports and publicity pertaining to the Dean's Fellowship, which was established in 1992 by Francille Firbaugh, following the 1991 New York State College of Human Ecology Conference "Rethinking Women and Home Economics in the 20th Century."
Recipients from 1992-2015 include: Nancy Berlage, Kathleen Babbitt, Julia Grant, Mary Summers, Carolyn Goldstein, Janet Hutchison, Karen Stupski, Bruce Pietrykowski, Amy Bentley, Richard Ahrens, Kathy Cooke, Megan Elias, Jan Scholl, Charlotte Biltekoff, Gabriella Petrick, Helen Veit, Mary-Anne Beecher, Karen Dunn-Haley, Gwen Kay, Anna Flaming, Anna Schatz, Allison Horrocks, Barbara Penner and Anna Myjak-Pycia.
Includes the 2006 undergraduate fellowship recipient, Corey Earle.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; Ahrens, Richard A.; Babbitt, Kathleen.; Beecher, Mary-Anne; Bentley, Amy, 1962-; Berlage, Nancy.; Cooke, Kathy.; Dunn-Haley, Karen; Earle, Corey Ryan.; Elias, Megan.; Firebaugh, Francille M., 1933-; Flaming, Anna.; Goldstein, Carolyn M., 1962-; Grant, Julia, 1953-; Horrocks, Allison; Hutchison, Janet.; Kay, Gwen; Myjak-Pycia, Anna; Patrick, Gabriella M.; Penner, Barbara; Pietrykowski, Bruce.; Schatz, Anna; Scholl, Jan (Jan Fleener); Stupski, Karen.; Summers, Mary.; Veit, Helen.; Weinstock, Tamar.; Cornell University--Administration.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Dean's Fellowship.
Subjects:
Home economics.; Nutrition.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Podcasts of presentations by Dean's Fellowship Recipients can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/3907
Papers by Undergraduate Fellowship Recipients can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/14388
- Content of Archival Box 23/2/3127 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Conference: Rethinking Women and Home Economics in the 20th Century, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Operation of the Fellowship Committee, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Total Applicant Pool (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Evaluation of Cornell Library Holdings by Fellowship Recipients (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Marketing for Fellowship Applicants, leaflets, letters and announcements (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Publicity (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Web Site and Links (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Funding Initiatives (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Initial Planning and Administration, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Kathleen Babbitt- Recipient, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Julia Grant- Recipient 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Nancy Berlage- Recipient, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Mary Summers- Recipient, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Carolyn Goldstein- Recipient 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Janet Hutchison - Recipient, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "Development of Food and Nutrition Labs at Cornell 1900-1935" Karen Skupski, Audio Cassette, 1997; tr.8172a (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Bruce Pietrykowski- Recipient, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Amy Bentley- Recipient, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Richard Ahrens- Special Award, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Summery Report Prepared for Dean Brannon and Response, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Kathy Cooke- Recipient, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Megan Elias- Recipient, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Centennial Celebration of College, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Jan Scholl- Recipient, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Charlotte Biltekoff- Recipient, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Gabriella Petrick- Recipient, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Helen Veit- Recipient, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Report to the Dean, April 2005, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Corey Earle-Undergraduate Recipient, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Correspondence, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Mary Ann Beecher-Recipient, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Karen Dunn Haley- Recipient, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Gwen Kay- Recipient, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Anna Flaming- Recipient, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Tamar Weinstock- Undergraduate Recipient - "Let us Hang Up the Dishpan and the Broom" The Pursuit of Culture in the Farmers Wives" Reading Course and the Cornell Study Clubs", 2009 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Rachel Louise Moran- Recipient, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Amrys Williams- Recipient, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Anna Schatz- Recipient, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- List of what former recipients are doing, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Article from "Human Ecology" magazine about Dean's Fellowship, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Allison Horrocks- Recipient, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Barbara Penner- Recipient, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Anna Myjak-Pycia- Recipient, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Jonathan Robins- Recipient, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Juliana Barton- Recipient, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Poster Anna Flaming's talk, 2010 (Folder 1)
- Poster Juliana Barton's talk, 2018 (Folder 1)